<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Posts on Weifan Zhou's Personal Blog</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in English Posts on Weifan Zhou's Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:11:47 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weifanz.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Game Review: Cities: Skylines (2): Health, Allocation &amp; Pollution</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/06/01/game-review-cities-skylines-2-health-allocation-pollution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:11:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/06/01/game-review-cities-skylines-2-health-allocation-pollution/</guid><description>In my last post, I mentioned the death and corrupted health system due to the traffic jams. These issues began in the second week of playing the game. Suddenly, people on the same streets and city blocks fell ill, but there weren't enough ambulances to transport them to the hospitals. I did not know why the number of patients abruptly increased, so I searched online and guessed it was because the first generation in the city had gotton older and natually developed illnesses.</description></item><item><title>Game Review: Cities: Skylines (1) -- Roads &amp; Population</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/05/31/game-review-cities-skylines-1-roads-population/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 21:23:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/05/31/game-review-cities-skylines-1-roads-population/</guid><description>I haven't played this game for long, but recently, my first city reached a population of 100k, which is a huge progress since I first download of Cities: Skylines in May.
On May 11, I got my first achievement, "Unpopular Mayor", with a 15% happiness rating on the first day I played. It might sound rediculous, as empty houses were automatically considered "unhappy", even though no one was living in those areas.</description></item><item><title>(Possible?) Psychology Article Review Helper Guide</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/20/possible-psychology-article-review-helper-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 07:55:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/20/possible-psychology-article-review-helper-guide/</guid><description>Reminder for those catching ddl in psyc paper:
If you are out of time, here are 2 options.
Choose an easy but shallow topic. Summarizing articles can be easy if your topic isn&amp;rsquo;t too hard, but you may struggle with minimum page requirement. Choose this pathway if you are not interested in psychology or you want to finish project as soon as possible. Choose a topic related to recent research or from an interdiciplinary research.</description></item><item><title>The Flaws of Psychology and CS Course Design (Revised on Apr 19)</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/03/the-flaws-of-psychology-and-cs-course-design-revised-on-apr-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 14:29:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/03/the-flaws-of-psychology-and-cs-course-design-revised-on-apr-19/</guid><description>Here is one thing: should beginners know the history of their majors?
This problem came up with learning Linked List, a type of data structure in CS. Though the professor had mentioned how linked lists are used in closing and opening tabs to avoid linear costs, I still had no idea when linear costs became an issue, who came up with linked lists as a solution, and how this solution was being widely used.</description></item><item><title>I Am Confused -- What's My Interest?</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/03/22/i-am-confused-whats-my-interest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 14:46:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/03/22/i-am-confused-whats-my-interest/</guid><description>Today is the academic advising day. There're gonna be 2 hours left to my course selection appointment because I memorized the appointment time wrong (lol). Now I have some time to write this post.
I got the available courses of Fall 2023 during the spring break, but I hesitated. Shall I add back Psychology major? Shall I choose math courses? Shall I try some new stuff? Or, am I that interested in data analysis, or am I lying to myself?</description></item><item><title>Finally Understand Class/Structure</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/22/finally-understand-class/structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:54:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/22/finally-understand-class/structure/</guid><description>I did not fully understand "Class" until this weekend I used code cademy and learned about structure. I was confused whether Class is like std or a type like int (I was thinking how types are defined). Now I know it's a datatype. And I realized why private and public are needed. Probably, for safety reasons, the developer doesn't wanna users to revise data, such as deposits, to be a billionaire (lol).</description></item><item><title>Coffee</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/20/coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:48:57 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/20/coffee/</guid><description>Coffee never works for me. I mean, unlike some of my friends whose heartrate speed up by coffee, nothing happens to me, and it was totally fine for me to sleep after drinking coffee. The problem is they can stay up late but waken up by coffee, which is impossible for me. And I was not obsessed by the coffee flavor, so I rarely drank it.
Two weeks ago I tried caramel frappuchino.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts About Math</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/15/some-thoughts-about-math/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 18:02:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/15/some-thoughts-about-math/</guid><description>This is my first English blog article. Probably there are some grammatical errors, and thanks for your patience. Recently I am reading [A Mathematician's Lament], a discussion about problems of traditional k12 math education. I was touched. The fisrt half of the book helped organize and speak out what I doubted about my junior high school math.
Below is my story. Math was the worst subject I performed in my junior high school.</description></item></channel></rss>