<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Posts on Weifan Zhou's Personal Blog</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in English Posts on Weifan Zhou's Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 16:16:14 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weifanz.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Blackout</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/07/25/blackout/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2024 16:16:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/07/25/blackout/</guid><description>The short novel was translated from my Chinese blog by ChatGPT. Also, ChatGPT added me an ending. In a world fractured by distrust towards governments plagued by wars, election fraud, and opaque finances, clans and communities governed their local affairs, while global issues were hotly debated over the internet. As technology advanced, debates grew fiercer, particularly over whether to abolish cash or automate primary education.
To navigate these tumultuous waters, the &amp;ldquo;Earth Committee&amp;rdquo; was established, comprising representatives from various global sectors.</description></item><item><title>Moral and Ethical Concern of Autonomous Weapons</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/05/08/moral-and-ethical-concern-of-autonomous-weapons/</link><pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 01:52:10 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/05/08/moral-and-ethical-concern-of-autonomous-weapons/</guid><description>Note: This is an assignment from my Cybertechnology Ethics (PHIL 222) class from Illinois Wesleyan University. The essay was finished in April 30, 2024.
In modern wars such as the Ukraine War, some advanced technologies like drones are used for killing enemies without soldiers going to the battlefield. Those drones have used artificial intelligence for targeting people, which raised people's concern about whether it is too cruel to use autonomous weapons in wars.</description></item><item><title>Initial Thoughts of Partial Differentiation</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/02/29/initial-thoughts-of-partial-differentiation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:15:04 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/02/29/initial-thoughts-of-partial-differentiation/</guid><description>As a person who&amp;rsquo;ve only completed Calc 1 &amp;amp; 2, I just started learning some partial differentiation. The symbol of partial differentiaion is a bit confused to me at first, but there&amp;rsquo;s an easier way of thinking about differentiaion in 3-dimentional cases: cutting cakes.
When you plan to cut a cake, you can either cut it in two ways: you can cut it from left to right, or from front to back.</description></item><item><title>Cope With Anxiety</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/02/29/cope-with-anxiety/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 16:04:00 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/02/29/cope-with-anxiety/</guid><description>This week, I tried to cope with my anxiety to a bunch of coursework. Something poped into my mind:
In my piano lesson, my Professor asked me: Flora, why you played those notes quiet? There's something in your mind than reminds you to play quiet. Try to play everything loud this week, so you no longer need to think about "quiet".
Yeah, previously I tried to print my readings out, so that I didn't need to rely on my iPad for reading assignments and then got distracted.</description></item><item><title>Reflection on Flaws of my CS377 British Car Accident Project</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/02/11/reflection-on-flaws-of-my-cs377-british-car-accident-project/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 16:53:55 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2024/02/11/reflection-on-flaws-of-my-cs377-british-car-accident-project/</guid><description>Last semester, I wanted to challenge myself a little bit when choosing the final project topic for my Applied Data Analysis class (you can view that on my GitHub). However, there were many flaws in the outcome, such as poor ROCs, ignoring seasons, no maps, and too many records being wiped out, etc., making the prediction less accurate.
Later, I realized that car accident datasets were spatial data, which was full of small disjuncts.</description></item><item><title>Cities: Skylines (5) -- Fire</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/11/28/cities-skylines-5--fire/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2023 12:44:14 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/11/28/cities-skylines-5--fire/</guid><description>Note: I have not experienced a wildfire in the Natural Disaster mod. More content will be added once I've enabled the Natural Disaster mod.
In the first few city stages, funds are too limited to construct fire stations on every street. So, it is important to see where fires are more likely to occur.
In Cities: Skylines, you can view fire risks in the menu by looking at each building's color.</description></item><item><title>Cities: Skylines (4) -- Water</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/11/23/cities-skylines-4--water/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 22:12:39 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/11/23/cities-skylines-4--water/</guid><description>In my second Cities: Skylines post, trash stations, which brought significant pollution, had a huge impact on residents' health nearby. In this post, I am going to introduce another source of pollution: sewage.
Imagine a river flowing from the north to the south, passing through a city. What if the water pump was placed in the south, at the bottom of the river, while the sewage drain was at the top of the river?</description></item><item><title>Empathy and Sympathy -- Based on Jungian Cognitive Functions</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/08/12/empathy-and-sympathy--based-on-jungian-cognitive-functions/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 10:29:42 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/08/12/empathy-and-sympathy--based-on-jungian-cognitive-functions/</guid><description>This article is a translation to my previous Chinese post written on May 18. However, there are some revisions. --------------------------
Many people have taken the MBTI test and claimed that they have changed from "xxxx" to "xxxx". However, this assertion is incorrect because 16-personality test is based on Jungian cognitive functions, which determine people's innate thinking process. It is likely that these individuals received inaccurate results in at least one MBTI test.</description></item><item><title>My Review With &lt;Industrial Society and Its Future></title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/07/31/my-review-with-industrial-society-and-its-future/</link><pubDate>Mon, 31 Jul 2023 11:06:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/07/31/my-review-with-industrial-society-and-its-future/</guid><description>Warning: This article may contain some offensive ideas. If you feel uncomfortable with this article, I apologize, and feel free to comment below and share your thoughts (if you have github accounts).
Industrial Society and Its Future was written by Ted Kaczynski, a math genius but eventually gave up his academic career and created bomb crimes in universities. He published this article on Washington Post in 1995 before he was caught.</description></item><item><title>Here is why: Email Verification Should be Completed Before a New Account is Created</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/07/13/here-is-why-email-verification-should-be-completed-before-a-new-account-is-created/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 21:03:55 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/07/13/here-is-why-email-verification-should-be-completed-before-a-new-account-is-created/</guid><description>I found the email verification system of Pearson wiered. It allows a new account to complete sign-up process before email verificaion, whereas on other websites, the account cannot be created or used until the user finishes email verification.
Here is the problem: If I mistakenly type the adress wrong twice, not just a typo but by entering a wrong domain name (for example, if I input ".com" instead of ".edu") and I never realize this error, I would never be able to complete email verification.</description></item><item><title>Linear Algebra Textbook Recommendation (If You're not Math Major)</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/07/13/linear-algebra-textbook-recommendation-if-youre-not-math-major/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Jul 2023 11:20:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/07/13/linear-algebra-textbook-recommendation-if-youre-not-math-major/</guid><description>If you are a computer science student, or other non-math majors, I recommend “Linear Algebra: Theory, Intuition, Code”, written by Mike X Cohen, as ONE OF your textbooks. Here are a few reasons why:
1. This textbook doesn't begin with Gauss elimination or linear equations; instead, it talks about vectors first. In my opinion, the book is more geometrically based. If you have some background knowledge of vectors from high school (for example, if you're from Mainland China), this textbook will help you connect your high school knowledge more effectively.</description></item><item><title>Cities Skylines (3): Transportation, Zones &amp; Trade</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/06/28/cities-skylines-3-transportation-zones-trade/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Jun 2023 00:48:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/06/28/cities-skylines-3-transportation-zones-trade/</guid><description>Unlike Civilization VI, there is no way to decide which state should join the trade in Cities: Skylines, and player can never determine which goods and products will be imported or exported from the city. However, the percentage of incoming and going products, listed in the sidebar, serves as an indication of trade. Trade occurs natrually based on needs, transportation, and zone allocation.
If a city produces electricity through coal or oil, it must import fuels.</description></item><item><title>Game Review: Cities: Skylines (2) -- Health, Allocation &amp; Pollution</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/06/01/game-review-cities-skylines-2--health-allocation-pollution/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 11:11:47 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/06/01/game-review-cities-skylines-2--health-allocation-pollution/</guid><description>In my last post, I mentioned the death and collapsed health system due to the traffic jams. These issues began in the second week of playing the game. Suddenly, people on the same streets and city blocks fell ill, but there weren't enough ambulances to transport them to the hospitals. I did not know why the number of patients abruptly increased, so I searched online and guessed it was because the first generation in the city had gotton older and natually developed illnesses.</description></item><item><title>Game Review: Cities: Skylines (1) -- Roads &amp; Population</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/05/31/game-review-cities-skylines-1--roads-population/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 May 2023 21:23:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/05/31/game-review-cities-skylines-1--roads-population/</guid><description>I haven't played this game for long, but recently, my first city reached a population of 100k, which is a huge progress since I first download of Cities: Skylines in May.
On May 11, I got my first achievement, "Unpopular Mayor", with a 15% happiness rating on the first day I played. It might sound rediculous, as empty houses were automatically considered "unhappy", even though no one was living in those areas.</description></item><item><title>(Possible?) Psychology Article Review Helper Guide</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/20/possible-psychology-article-review-helper-guide/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Apr 2023 07:55:48 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/20/possible-psychology-article-review-helper-guide/</guid><description>Reminder for those catching ddl in psyc paper:
If you are out of time, here are 2 options.
Choose an easy but shallow topic. Summarizing articles can be easy if your topic isn&amp;rsquo;t too hard, but you may struggle with minimum page requirement. Choose this pathway if you are not interested in psychology or you want to finish project as soon as possible. Choose a topic related to recent research or from an interdiciplinary research.</description></item><item><title>The Flaws of Psychology and CS Course Design (Revised on Apr 19)</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/03/the-flaws-of-psychology-and-cs-course-design-revised-on-apr-19/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Apr 2023 14:29:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/04/03/the-flaws-of-psychology-and-cs-course-design-revised-on-apr-19/</guid><description>Here is one thing: should beginners know the history of their majors?
This problem came up with learning Linked List, a type of data structure in CS. Though the professor had mentioned how linked lists are used in closing and opening tabs to avoid linear costs, I still had no idea when linear costs became an issue, who came up with linked lists as a solution, and how this solution was being widely used.</description></item><item><title>I Am Confused -- What's My Interest?</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/03/22/i-am-confused--whats-my-interest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 14:46:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/03/22/i-am-confused--whats-my-interest/</guid><description>Today is the academic advising day. There're gonna be 2 hours left to my course selection appointment because I memorized the appointment time wrong (lol). Now I have some time to write this post.
I got the available courses of Fall 2023 during the spring break, but I hesitated. Shall I add back Psychology major? Shall I choose math courses? Shall I try some new stuff? Or, am I that interested in data analysis, or am I lying to myself?</description></item><item><title>Finally Understand Class/Structure</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/22/finally-understand-class/structure/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:54:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/22/finally-understand-class/structure/</guid><description>I did not fully understand "Class" until this weekend I used code cademy and learned about structure. I was confused whether Class is like std or a type like int (I was thinking how types are defined). Now I know it's a datatype. And I realized why private and public are needed. Probably, for safety reasons, the developer doesn't wanna users to revise data, such as deposits, to be a billionaire (lol).</description></item><item><title>Coffee</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/20/coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:48:57 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/20/coffee/</guid><description>Coffee never works for me. I mean, unlike some of my friends whose heartrate speed up by coffee, nothing happens to me, and it was totally fine for me to sleep after drinking coffee. The problem is they can stay up late but waken up by coffee, which is impossible for me. And I was not obsessed by the coffee flavor, so I rarely drank it.
Two weeks ago I tried caramel frappuchino.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts About Math</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/15/some-thoughts-about-math/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 18:02:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/15/some-thoughts-about-math/</guid><description>This is my first English blog article. Probably there are some grammatical errors, and thanks for your patience. Recently I am reading [A Mathematician's Lament], a discussion about problems of traditional k12 math education. I was touched. The fisrt half of the book helped organize and speak out what I doubted about my junior high school math.
Below is my story. Math was the worst subject I performed in my junior high school.</description></item></channel></rss>