<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>English Posts on Weifan Zhou's Personal Blog</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/posts/</link><description>Recent content in English Posts on Weifan Zhou's Personal Blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 14:46:53 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://weifanz.github.io/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I Am Confused -- What's My Interest?</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/03/22/i-am-confused-whats-my-interest/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2023 14:46:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/03/22/i-am-confused-whats-my-interest/</guid><description>Today is the academic advising day. There're gonna be 2 hours left to my course selection appointment because I memorized the appointment time wrong (lol). Now I have some time to write this post.
I got the available courses of Fall 2023 during the spring break, but I hesitated. Shall I add back Psychology major? Shall I choose math courses? Shall I try some new stuff? Or, am I that interested in data analysis, or am I lying to myself?</description></item><item><title>Finally Understand [Class]</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/22/finally-understand-class/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 00:54:15 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/22/finally-understand-class/</guid><description>I did not fully understand &amp;ldquo;Class&amp;rdquo; until this weekend I used code cademy and learned about structure. I was confused whether Class is like std or a type like int (I was thinking how types are defined). Now I know it&amp;rsquo;s a datatype. And I realized why private and public are needed. Probably, for safety reasons, the developer doesn&amp;rsquo;t wanna users to revise data, such as deposits, to be a billionaire (lol).</description></item><item><title>Coffee</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/20/coffee/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 15:48:57 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/20/coffee/</guid><description>Coffee never works for me. I mean, unlike some of my friends whose heartrate speed up by coffee, nothing happens to me, and it was totally fine for me to sleep after drinking coffee. The problem is they can stay up late but waken up by coffee, which is impossible for me. And I was not obsessed by the coffee flavor, so I rarely drank it.
Two weeks ago I tried caramel frappuchino.</description></item><item><title>Some Thoughts About Math</title><link>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/15/some-thoughts-about-math/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 18:02:29 -0600</pubDate><guid>https://weifanz.github.io/en/2023/02/15/some-thoughts-about-math/</guid><description>This is my first English blog article. Probably there are some grammatical errors, and thanks for your patience. Recently I am reading [A Mathematician's Lament], a discussion about problems of traditional k12 math education. I was touched. The fisrt half of the book helped organize and speak out what I doubted about my junior high school math.
Below is my story. Math was the worst subject I performed in my junior high school.</description></item></channel></rss>